### ADRIAN GAR<u>MENDIA</u>

## FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- -Team Oriented
- -Driven
- -Leade
- -Critical Thinker
- -Dependable
- -Problem Solver

### **TECHNOLOGIES**

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript React .Net

C#

### **CONTACT DETAILS**

143 Antler Ridge Cir., Nashville, Tennessee 37214

dejima@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/adriangarmendia/

https://github.com/AdiGarmendia

615-516-1112

### **ABOUT**

My professional career began in broadcasting where I spent my days with other creative people editing videos, creating news shows, running cameras and finally moving on to being a quality control technician. After broadcasting I moved on to a 13 year career with FedEx Express as a courier, dangerous goods specialist and a operations lead. A twist in life gave me the opportunity to learn an entirely new career in software development that I found through Nashville Software School. It's been a joy continuing my team oriented ways in a new passion and creating apps.

### **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School — Nashville, Tennessee 2019-2020 Full Stack Software Developer

Nashville State Junior College — Nashville, Tennessee 2005

A+ & Network+

Faulkner State Junior College — Bay Minette, Alabama 1993-1996 Criminal Justice

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School 2019-2020

Full time boot camp for full stack development Hands on application and experience with

- -HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, C#, .net
- -Use and creation of multiple API's
- -Working with SCRUM methodology for team projects
- -Use of Git and GitHub for version control

#### COURIER

FedEx Express Nashville Tennessee & Mobile Alabama 2006-2019

- -Picked up and delivered packages that included medical specimens and hazardous materials daily
- -Built and maintained professional relationships with customers
- -Communicated route progress to dispatch, noting traffic and construction issues to avoid delays for critical deliveries
- -Established lasting relationships with customers by delivering packages on time, interacting professionally and responding promptly to questions.

### ADRIAN GARMENDIA

## FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- -Team Oriented
- -Driver
- -Leade
- Critical Thinker
- -Dependable
- --Problem Solvei

### **INTERESTING FACTS**

- -Second generation Cuban American
- -Was a member of a National Championship winning Rugby club
- -Loves Baseball and Mardi Gras

### **CONTACT DETAILS**

143 Antler Ridge Cir., Nashville, Tennessee 37214

dejima@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/adriangarmendia/

https://github.com/AdiGarmendia

615-516-1112

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

### DANGEROUS GOODS SPECIALIST

FedEx Express 2011-2016

- -Inspected hazardous material shipments for compliance with IADA regulations for air transportation
- -Input data into database for tracking and clearance on the world wide system

### Operations Lead

FedEx Express 2011-2014

- -Served as the PM reload lead. I coordinated the sort and insured the trailer pulled on time each night
- -Ran Saturday operations that included leading the sort, route balancing, dispatching and the monitoring of the teams progress -Created detailed reports of the operation and filed it with management
- -Lead a team of 15 to 20 individuals

### Accounting Assistant

Coastal Insulation of Louisiana 2005-2006

-Assisted the Accountant in preparing Tax reports and the paying of company bills. Also handled the filing of documents.

### Quality Control Technician

Sky Latin America 2000-2005

- -Responsible for caching all material into our system and then transferring them to their playout devices
- -Assure the quality of all material and make dubs of pay per view movies and insert our logo into the movie
- -Also have experience with encoding subtitles into video

#### Video Editor

WSVN 7 News June 2000-August 2000

-Worked as a video editor for the morning news cast. Edited on beta format

WPMI 15 News 1999-2000

- -Worked in both Master Control and News
- -Dubbed commercial spots into our VR commercial computer, ran shows by queuing them up, following the cue sheets and switching them
- -Handled paperwork and monitoring of equipment in Master Control to go along with the switching of shows between the show and commercials
- -Extensive experience in studio camera operations
- -Edited video footage for the Morning show.